tessituranetwork.com 2019-02-27

# Privacy Policy

At Tessitura Network (“Tessitura”, “Network”, “we” or “us”), we respect and protect your privacy rights. This Privacy Policy describes:

  * When and what information we collect on our websites and through use of our online services (the "Services"), or by any of our service providers through our website.
  * How we use Personal Information we collect.
  * Your rights regarding your Personal Information.

This Policy describes Network's practices regarding the collection, use, and retention of Personal Information. "Personal Information" is information through which you can be directly or indirectly identified, e.g. your name, your e-mail address and items you purchased (provided we can connect them to your e-mail/customer account) "Individual Customers" refers to licensees/members of Tessitura software and their designated employees.

By using this website or our products and services, you consent to our collection, use and disclosure of your Personal Information as set out in this Privacy Policy. Tessitura has agreements (the “Agreements”) with Individual Customers that contain other provisions with respect to Personal Information. 

The terms and conditions of the Agreements are in addition to this Privacy Policy and take precedence over this Privacy Policy in the event of any conflict. This includes, without limitation, the terms of our Data Processing Agreement for those Individual Customers for whom Tessitura performs data processing. 

### Use of Personal Information

The information that we collect from Individual Customers is used for licensing Tessitura software and supporting Tessitura Network members in their use of that software, managing transactions, reporting, invoicing, renewals, and other operations related to providing services and products to the Individual Customer.

When we host Tessitura software on behalf of a licensee/member, Tessitura Network serves as a service provider. In our capacity as a service provider, we will receive, store, and/or process Personal Information. In such cases, we are acting as a data processor and will process the Personal Information on behalf of and under the direction of our Individual Customers. The information that we store for our Individual Customers in this capacity is controlled by Individual Customers for managing transactions, reporting, invoicing, renewals, other operations related to providing services to their customers. Tessitura Network uses Personal Information that it collects directly from its Individual Customers and for its partners indirectly in its role as a service provider for the following business purposes, without limitation:

  * maintaining and supporting its products, delivering and providing the requested products/services, and complying with its contractual obligations related thereto (including managing transactions, reporting, invoices, renewals, and other operations related to providing services to an Individual Customer);
  * satisfying governmental reporting, tax, and other requirements (e.g., import/export);
  * storing and processing data, including Personal Information, in computer databases and servers located in the United States, Europe, and Australia;
  * verifying identity (e.g., for online access to accounts), as requested by the Individual Customer;
  * for other business-related purposes permitted or required under applicable local law and regulation;
  * to protect the security or integrity of our websites and our business
  * and as otherwise required by law.

### Disclosures and Onward Transfers of Personal Information of Individual Customers

Tessitura Network never discloses or sells Personal Information to Third Parties, except as expressly set forth herein.

Unless an Agreement provides otherwise, we will only disclose personally identifiable information that we collect or you provide as described in this Privacy Policy:

  * To contractors, service providers and other third parties we use to support our business and who are bound by contractual obligations to keep Personal Information confidential and use it only for the purposes for which we disclose it to them.
  * To fulfill the purpose for which you provide it.
  * For any other purpose disclosed by us when you provide the information.
  * With your consent.

We may share your Personal Information where necessary in order to comply with any legal obligation, legal requests by public authorities, including requests to meet national security or law enforcement requirements, to protect and defend us, our subsidiaries and affiliates and all of our officers, directors, employees, attorneys, agents, contractors, and partners, in connection with any legal action, claim or dispute or in order to enforce or apply our terms of use and other agreements.

We may transfer your Personal Information to a third party in the event of a transfer of all or some of our assets to a third party, provided that the third party agrees to adhere to terms similar to those of this Privacy Policy. We will provide you with an opportunity to reject the transfer of your Personal Information in such cases.

We may disclose aggregated, non-personal information about website users without restriction.

###  Retention

We will keep your Personal Information for as long as necessary for the purposes described herein or as long as we are required by law. After this your Personal Information will be deleted. We cannot remove your Personal Information when there is a legal storage requirement, such as accounting rules or when there are other legal grounds to keep the data, such as an ongoing contractual relationship.

###  Security

The security of your Personal Information is important to us. Accordingly, while no set of privacy and security standards or safeguards is 100% secure, we take steps to ensure any information that you share with us is kept secure and strictly confidential in accordance with this policy. We take various precautions to protect information from loss, misuse and unauthorized access, collection, use, disclosure, copying, modification, alteration, destruction or similar risks. Tessitura Network personnel may access and use Personal Information only if they are authorized to do so and only for the purpose for which they are authorized.

### California Residents

Under California law, California residents who have an established business relationship with Network may make a written request to Network about how we have shared their Personal Information with third parties for direct marketing purposes during the prior calendar year. In response to a written request, Network is allowed to provide a cost-free means to opt-out of such sharing.

Network does not share your Personal Information with third parties for direct marketing purposes and therefore is not required to provide such a procedure; however, if you would like to access, correct or request deletion of your Personal Information in Network’s possession please follow the cost-free procedures set forth herein.

### Children's Online Privacy Protection Act (“COPPA”)

We do not knowingly collect, maintain, or use Personal Information from our Website about children under the age of 13. We request that persons under the age of 13 not use our Website. We will never knowingly request Personal Information from a child under the age of 13. If we become aware that a child under the age of 13 has sent Personal Information to us, we will remove his or her Personal Information from our files. For the purpose of conference registration, an Individual User may submit a child’s information as an event guest. By submitting your child’s information you consent to our privacy policy on behalf of your child. 

### Services Location 

The Services for the Individual Customers are operated in the United States. If you are located outside the United States, please be aware that information we collect, including Personal Information, may be transferred to, processed, and stored in the United States. By using the Services or providing us with any information, you consent to the transfer, processing, and storage of your information in the United States. To the maximum extent allowed by applicable law, you are also consenting to the application of United States federal and Texas state law in all matters concerning the Services and this Privacy Policy.

###  Password Protected Section of the Website 

Access to the password protected section of the website (“Licensee Section” or “Section”) is restricted to such person(s) who are licensees of Tessitura Software or employees of Tessitura or those separately authorized for entry by Tessitura.

Passwords are issued on a per person basis and may be used only by the individual to whom the password is issued. All persons who access the Licensee Section agree to not share with or provide access to this Section or share their password with anyone else, and also agree to not discuss pricing practices, terms or similar issues.

Licensees are responsible for maintaining the security of any passwords issued by Tessitura to their employees and agree to promptly notify Tessitura in the event of a misappropriation or unauthorized disclosure of a password to a third party.

### Email Subscription Management 

As a member of Tessitura Network, you can sign up to receive Tessitura Network business and education email communications. If you choose to opt out of these lists, you may do so at any time by managing the “Subscriptions” area on this website’s logged in My Account page, or from the “unsubscribe” mechanism at the bottom of all Tessitura Network email.

### Confidentiality

You agree not to distribute or share any information made available to you on the website except and solely to the extent reasonably necessary to operate your business in the ordinary course and consistent with any terms to which the information is expressly made subject where posted, any other agreements, such as licenses for the Tessitura Software or as restricted by applicable confidentiality agreements. You further agree not to use, rent, or sell for marketing or other commercial purposes any data obtained from this website including user addresses, and any user web postings including comments or statements.

###  IP Addresses

An Internet protocol (“IP”) address is a numeric code, for example, “152.163.207.197.” This code is used to communicate between your Internet service provider and the World Wide Web. The IP address does not identify you individually. Tessitura logs inbound IP addresses to administer our website and to compile aggregate information on site traffic for internal use.

###  Cookies

Cookies (and similar files such as single pixel GIFs, web beacons or tags) are small computer files written to your computer when you visit websites. You have the option of setting your browser to refuse Cookies although this may diminish your ability to utilize the website.

Tessitura uses Cookies to collect anonymous, non-personal information to make your use of the website easier and allow Tessitura to track website usage. For example, when you check the “Remember my Email” checkbox at Login, a Cookie will remember your email address.

### Links to Other Websites

Tessitura assumes no responsibility for any content, information collected, terms and conditions or privacy rules maintained on any linked site and we strongly encourage you to examine the privacy policies contained on these sites. Please inform us at webmaster@tessituranetwork.com about any concerns you may have regarding any of our linked sites.

### Access to and Your Rights Regarding Your Personal Information 

Right to Access. Individual Customers have the right to know what Personal Information about them is included in our databases and to ensure that such Personal Information is accurate and relevant for the purposes for which Tessitura Network collected it. Individual Customers may review their own Personal Information stored in the databases and correct, erase, or block any data. Upon reasonable request, Tessitura Network allows Individual Customers access to their Personal Information, in order to erase or to correct or amend such data where inaccurate. Individual Customers may edit their Personal Information by logging into their account profile at at www.tessituranetwork.com or by contacting Tessitura Network by phone at 888-643-5778 or by email at [privacy@tessituranetwork.com](mailto:privacy@tessituranetwork.com?subject=Inquiry). In making modifications to their Personal Information, Individual Customers must provide only truthful, complete, and accurate information. To request erasure of Personal Information, Individual Customers should submit a written request to Tessitura Network.

Satisfying Requests for Access, Modifications, and Corrections. Tessitura Network will endeavor to respond in a timely manner to all reasonable written requests to view, modify, inactivate, or erase Personal Information. You may access information we hold about you, request a correction where data is incorrect or a deletion of your data, unless we have to keep your data for legal reasons.

Questions and Concerns. We encourage you to address any concerns you may have regarding our use of your Personal Information by using the contact details provided herein.

### Changes to this Policy

This Policy may be amended from time to time, consistent with applicable data protection and privacy laws and principles. We will make employees available of changes to this policy either by posting to our intranet, through email, or other means. We will notify Individual Customers if we make changes that materially affect the way we handle Personal Information previously collected, and we will allow them to choose whether their Personal Information may be used in any materially different manner.

### Questions or Complaints

Customers may contact Tessitura Network with questions or complaints concerning this Policy at the following address: [privacy@tessituranetwork.com](mailto:privacy@tessituranetwork.com). You may also write us at:

Tessitura Network, Inc.   
P.O. Box 670245  
Dallas, TX  75367-0245

### Enforcement and Dispute Resolution

Tessitura Network commits to resolve complaints about your privacy and our collection or use of your Personal Information. Individuals with questions or concerns about the use of their Personal Information should contact us at: [privacy@tessituranetwork.com](mailto:privacy@tessituranetwork.com?subject=Inquiry).

If a Customer's question or concern cannot be satisfied through this process Tessitura Network has further committed to refer unresolved privacy complaints to an independent dispute resolution mechanism operated by the International Centre for Dispute Resolution/American Arbitration Association (ICDR/AAA).

### EU Residents and General Data Protection Regulation

With respect to personal data, Tessitura Network commits to cooperate with the General Data Protection Act. We also commit to comply with the advice given by EU data protection authorities with regard to human resources data transferred from the EU in the context of the employment relationship. 

Our basis for processing personal information is:

  1. To administer, monitor and update this website
  2. To manage our relationship and inquiries from you
  3. To comply with legal obligations

Please contact us at [privacy@tessituranetwork.com](mailto:privacy@tessituranetwork.com?subject=Inquiry) if you need details about the specific legal ground we are relying on to process your personal data.

_Version updated May, 2018_
